<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>One war file, multiple configs</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="One war file, multiple configs">
            <p>
                Magnolia 2.1 (from RC3) introduced a new feature that makes customizing one war for author vs. public
                vs. some other server a bit easier. No need to keep two or more build trees around and in sync anymore.
            </p>
            <p>
                By default it's there, but not enabled. You'll see it as a default folder in
                <code>WEB-INF/config</code>
                . In that default folder is a readme.txt that gives some info, but not a lot. First, let me provide that
                readme here:
            </p>
            <source>
                <![CDATA[
Default configuration directory used with info.magnolia.cms.servlets.MgnlServletContextListener.

Using the Magnolia PropertyInitializer you can easily bundle in the same webapp different set of configurations
which are automatically applied dependending on the server name or the webapp name.
By default the initializer will try to search for the file in different location with different combination of
servername and webapp: the default fallback directory will be used if
no other environment-specific directory has been added.

This is the list of location where the initializer will try to find a configuration file (can be overridden using the
magnolia.initialization.file context parameter in WEB.xml);

 *     WEB-INF/config/${servername}/${webapp}/magnolia.properties,
 *     WEB-INF/config/${servername}/magnolia.properties,
 *     WEB-INF/config/${webapp}/magnolia.properties,
 *     WEB-INF/config/default/magnolia.properties,
 *     WEB-INF/config/magnolia.properties
]]>
            </source>
            <p>Now to set it up. That's relatively simple:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    Create a folder under
                    <code>WEB-INF/config</code>
                    for each separate config naming them to match the name of the webapp. If you're deploying on
                    different servers, nest these inside another folder named after your server. For instance if
                    developing a
                    <code>magnoliaAuthor</code>
                    and
                    <code>magnoliaPublic</code>
                    config, you'll have folders
                    <code>/WEB-INF/config/magnoliaAuthor</code>
                    and
                    <code>/WEB-INF/config/magnoliaPublic</code>
                    . If dealing with different servers, it might look like
                    <code>/WEB-INF/config/server1.com/magnoliaAuthor</code>
                    and
                    <code>/WEB-INF/config/server2.com/magnoliaPublic</code>
                    .
                </li>
                <li>
                    Copy the default folder's contents in to each folder and customize for each separate instance as
                    needed. One of those things you'll probably want to change consistently is the
                    <code>magnolia.root.sysproperty</code>
                    value to something unique. Then change the
                    <code>log4j.xml</code>
                    files to match this new value. Finally change the log4j.config value in magnolia.properties to point
                    to your customized log4j.xml file.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Open web.xml and comment out both the listener section for the standard initializer
                    <code>info.magnolia.cms.servlets.Initializer</code>
                    and the following context-param blocks. I would comment at first just to make it easy to role back
                    if things don't work out right. Delete later when things are working well.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Add the following to your web.xml:
                    <source>
                        <![CDATA[
    <listener>
      <description>Magnolia Property Initializer</description>
      <display-name>propertyInitializer</display-name>
      <listener-class>info.magnolia.cms.servlets.MgnlServletContextListener</listener-class>
    </listener>

    <context-param>
      <param-name>magnolia.initialization.file</param-name>
      <param-value>
        WEB-INF/config/${servername}/${webapp}/magnolia.properties,
        WEB-INF/config/${servername}/magnolia.properties,
        WEB-INF/config/${webapp}/magnolia.properties,
        WEB-INF/config/default/magnolia.properties,
        WEB-INF/config/magnolia.properties
      </param-value>
    </context-param>
]]>
                    </source>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Save and your done. Deploy and watch the magnolia-debug.log files for any gotchas. It never fails
                    for me to miss a setting at first and find out about it later when I'm analyzing the logs. Just
                    change the name of your webapp, deploy, and the config used will change as well.
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                The list of paths in the magnolia.initialization.file context param above isn't anything magic. Define
                it as you like, what's shown here is the default used if it was missing. If you aren't deploying against
                different servers, take out the top two and work with the last three. It'll try in order from first to
                last until it finds a magnolia.properties file.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
