<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Subscribers</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Activation">
			<subsection name="About activation">
				<p>
					When someone changes something in the "authoring" instance of the application
					the change initially won't have any effect on the public instance. In order to
					take effect on the public "subscriber" instance(s), the change needs to be
					"activated" - in a properly configured Magnolia setup this then pushes the
					changes to the public instance.
				</p>
				<p>
					Virtually every type of node can be activated
					and pushed to subscriber servers - not just web pages, this is important. When
					you look at the administration console of the authoring app you'll see a lot of
					little red lights next to everything, a red light indicates that that particular
					node is not published, a green light indicates that it has been published (but
					see below for caveats), and a yellow light indicates that you've changed
					something since it was last activated and you'll need to activate it again to
					push the changes to the public server.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="How Activation works">
				<p>
					In the Config/subscribers/subscriberConfig section of the authoring app you can
					set up details of what machines to activate changes to.
					You'll normally be pushing activated nodes to the public instance, but
					one can list several machines in this list for mirroring purposes, or
					other arcane setups. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Editing the node is reasonably self explanatory - you point
					it at your public server. Please make sure that activation works after you 
					have configured a new subscriber. Create a new page, activate it and see if 
					it shows up where it should (i.e. at the subscribing instance). Watch the logs 
					if it does not, they will tell you why activation fails.
					
					The GUI will make sure that you cannot activate unless an active subscriber is configured, 
					but <b>Magnolia doesn't double-check if activation has actually worked, 
					and will show the node as published even if it might have failed. </b>
				</p>
				<p>
					One reason why activation can fail is that you lack the permission 
					on the subscriber to actually write content where you wish to write it to.
					<b>When you activate something in the authoring server it uses your username and password to
					log into the subscribing server to actually do the publishing. </b> This means that
					unless there is a user on the subscribing machine (the public server) with your
					username and password and privileges then the activation process will fail silently. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Since users and roles are nodes just like any other they can
					be "activated" too. If you create a new user on the
					authoring instance, remember to "activate" that user so that the users details
					will be pushed to the subscriber server(s). One thing I really need to stress
					again, because it was very counterintuitive for me, is that there appears to be
					NO synchronisation process between the servers - the authoring server merely
					pushes changes on demand to the subscribing server. This seems to make things
					extremely brittle - if the authoring server and the public server get out of
					sync for some reason it's very hard to tell what gone wrong and very hard to fix
					it. The worst case of this appears to be if you change a users' password and
					forget to "activate" the change - that user will then be unable to make any
					changes to the subscriber server. 
					If the user in question is the superuser very awkward things can result.
				</p>
			</subsection>

		</section>

		<section name="Subscribers">
			<p>
				Like any system, Magnolia has a number of concepts you should be aware of before you
				get started with installations.
				<ul>
					<li>
						usually, Magnolia is set up in such a way that you have one instance running
						as the authoring system, one as the public system. This provides
						flexibility, scalability and security.
					</li>
					<li>
						if an instance is author or public is determined by a setting in the Config
						GUI. Setting isAdmin to true will generally let you edit pages etc.. Set it
						to false for public instances
					</li>
					<li>
						to get content from the authoring instance to the public instance(s), you
						use a mechanism called &quot;activation&quot;, which is executed from the
						GUI. Activation pushes content from the source instance (the one you are
						using when you click activate) to its
						<strong>subscribers</strong>
					</li>
					<li>
						there can be any number of subscribers. Subscribers are configured through
						the GUI (see config). Usually, there is one subscriber only, called the
						&quot;public instance&quot;

					</li>
					<li>
						Magnolia is delivered as a single war file which per default is set up as
						&quot;authoring&quot;
					</li>
					<li>to add a public instance, read below.</li>
					<li>
						you control the public instance from the author environment through means of
						activating content from the author environment to its subscriber(s)
					</li>
				</ul>

				<img src="../images/subscribers.png" />
			</p>
		</section>


	</body>
</document>