<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Building a page template</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="3. Building a page template">
            <p>
                A Web page is based on a so called "Page Template". In a dynamic world (like a CMS) the Template
                consists of a server side script, which is executed and the result is returned to the Client. The
                "Quickstart Template" we have created refers to
                <source>templates/jsp/quickstart/main.jsp</source>
                This path/file has been defined in the previous section. The
                <code>templates/jsp/quickstart</code>
                directory can contain several "templates" (meaning: several template scripts), since any template can
                include other templates (e.g.
                <code>main.jsp</code>
                can include templates like
                <code>navigation.jsp</code>
                ,
                <code>content.jsp</code>
                , etc.).
            </p>
            <p>
                <strong>
                    WARNING: even though this file is in UTF8, be warned that template directories and names MUST be in
                    ASCII.
                </strong>
            </p>
            <p>
                What does a page template look like? First of all, we use JSP to define the layout of the page. Second
                we have defined a number of tags that will make your life easier (more about this later).
            </p>
            <p>So lets get started. Let us line up that text editor and enter the magic words:</p>
            <source>
                <![CDATA[
<jsp:root version="2.0" xmlns:jsp="http://java.sun.com/JSP/Page" xmlns:cms="cms-taglib"
    xmlns:cmsu="cms-util-taglib" xmlns:c="http://java.sun.com/jsp/jstl/core">

</jsp:root>
                ]]>
            </source>
            <p>This will include the standard JSTL (which we will need later) and the Magnolia tag-libraries.</p>
            <p>
                <strong>
                    Sample templates included in the magnolia distribution and snippets in this tutorial make use of the
                    jsp/xml (also known as jspx) sintax. You are of course free to build your templates using plain,
                    non-xml, jsp code. For a quick jsp/jspx conversion guide you can take a look at
                    <a href="http://java.sun.com/products/jsp/syntax/2.0/card20.pdf">
                        http://java.sun.com/products/jsp/syntax/2.0/card20.pdf
                    </a>
                </strong>
            </p>
            <p>
                Now lets start the
                <code>HTML</code>
                and
                <code>HEAD</code>
                .
            </p>
            <source>
                <![CDATA[
<jsp:root version="2.0" xmlns:jsp="http://java.sun.com/JSP/Page" xmlns:cms="cms-taglib"
    xmlns:cmsu="cms-util-taglib" xmlns:c="http://java.sun.com/jsp/jstl/core">
    <jsp:directive.page contentType="text/html; charset=utf-8" />
    <html>
      <head>
        <title>
          <cms:out nodeDataName="title" />
        </title>
      </head>
    </html>
</jsp:root>
]]>
            </source>
            <p>
                When creating a new Web Page you define a "title" as well. This property is available for every Web page
                you create. We get the content of property "title" with the cms-tag
                <code>out</code>
                ...
            </p>
            <p>
                On we move with the
                <code>body</code>
                :
            </p>
            <source>
                <![CDATA[
...
  </head>
  <body style="background-color:#fff" >
    <cms:mainBar paragraph="samplesPageProperties" />
    <h2>Hello World</h2>
  </body>
</html>
...
]]>
            </source>
            <p>
                Let us save the file in the template directory (in this case
                <code>templates/jsp/quickstart/main.jsp</code>
                ). You will need to create the directory first, as it is completely up to you how you name your
                templates, and "quickstart" is just an example for the purpose of this tutorial.
            </p>
            <p>
                There is no need to restart Tomcat if you create or change jsp files.
                <br />
                Create a new Web page, choose the freshly defined template, and view the result (by clicking on the
                newly created page). Here we have our first working web page template, containing the Magnolia-specific
                "Main Bar" and our message to the world.
            </p>
            <p>
                <img src="../images/qs/03_magnolia_quickstartWebPage.png" />
            </p>
            <p>Congratulations! You have just created your first working template in Magnolia.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
