<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Refining the page template - adding a custom property</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="4. Refining the page template - adding a custom property">
            <p>
                So let us explore some more details. First of all you will have noticed the
                <source>
                    <![CDATA[<cms:mainBar paragraph="samplesPageProperties" />]]>
                </source>
            </p>
            <p>
                tag. As you have seen when you viewed your first page, a green bar will be shown across the top of the
                page, and lets you access a number of admin options - at the moment switch to preview mode, go to the
                administration environment or show the page properties dialog box.
            </p>
            <p>-- short background intermission --</p>
            <p>
                This bar will only be visible on admin pages. So what is the difference between an authoring page and a
                public page? Well, there really is none. Magnolia has the concept of stages, where we usually have at
                least an authoring and a public stage, each corresponding to its own instance of the application. So if
                this page is displayed on an authoring instance, the admin bars will be visible. If the page is
                displayed on a public instance, the admin bars will not be shown. If an instance is public or authoring
                is determined by the property
                <code>Config/server/admin</code>
                .
            </p>
            <p>-- end of intermission --</p>
            <p>
                So on we move. If you click on "Properties" in the "mainBar", a page properties dialog will be fired up.
                A dialog defines the model (in MVC parlance). While the dialog defines which properties you want to
                collect and store in the repository, the template defines which of these will be rendered as output -
                and how.
            </p>
            <p>
                Dialogs are defined through the administration GUI and reside under
                <source><![CDATA[Config/modules/templating/dialogs]]></source>
            </p>
            <p>
                Which dialog is displayed when we click on the "Properties" button? As stated earlier, a paragraph
                definition maps a template to a dialog. Paragraphs are defined in
                <source><![CDATA[Config/modules/templating/Paragraphs]]></source>
            </p>
            <p>
                The "mainBar" tag points to a paragraph definition, and the paragraph entry points to the dialog being
                displayed. The idea behind this redirection is that different templates can use the same dialog
                definitions. This makes it easy to switch the look and feel of a site.
            </p>
            <p>
                To define and use custom page properties we need to:
                <ol>
                    <li>Create a custom dialog and define the desired custom property.</li>
                    <li>Define a paragraph pointing to (1).</li>
                    <li>Adapt the page template pointing to (2) and displaying the custom property.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <subsection name="4.1 Create a custom dialog">
                <p>
                    Four our example, create a folder called "quickstart".
                    <br />
                    Right-click on
                    <code>Config/modules/templating/dialogs</code>
                    and select "New folder":
                    <source><![CDATA[Config/modules/templating/dialogs/quickstart]]></source>
                </p>
                <p>
                    Copy the sample dialog with a right-click on
                    <code>Config/modules/templating/samples/pageProperties</code>
                    , select "Copy" and click on
                    <code>Config/modules/templating/dialogs/quickstart</code>
                    .
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[from

Config/modules/templating/samples/pageProperties

to

Config/modules/templating/dialogs/quickstart/pageProperties]]>
                </source>
                <p>
                    As with page templates and paragraphs (as we will see later) the structure contains data nodes
                    defining properties of the dialog. Let us add a data node for the background color of our page.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <img src="../images/qs/04_magnolia_quickstartPageProperties.png" />
                </p>
                <p>
                    Thus we have a custom dialog for page properties that allows us to store our desired background
                    color.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="4.2 Create a Paragraph Definition pointing to our custom dialog">
                <p>
                    <source><![CDATA[Copy

Config/modules/templating/Paragraphs/samplesPageProperties

to

Config/modules/templating/Paragraphs/quickstartPageProperties

and change name and dialogPath]]>
                    </source>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <img src="../images/qs/04_magnolia_quickstartParagraphPageProperties.png" />
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="4.3 Adapt the Page Template">
                <p>
                    We need to change the page template's "mainBar" paragraph-Parameter to point to our paragraph
                    definition and adapt the page template to use our new background color property.
                </p>
                <p>
                    We fire up the page template again (
                    <code>/templates/jsp/quickstart/main.jsp</code>
                    ) and replace
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[<cms:mainBar paragraph="samplesPageProperties" />

with

<cms:mainBar paragraph="quickstartPageProperties" />]]>
                </source>
                <p>
                    Since we now use our custom mapping between the jsp (view) and the dialog definition (model), let us
                    use the background color property by changing
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[<body style="background-color:#fff" >]]></source>
                with
                <source><![CDATA[<cms:setNode var="pageProperties" /> <!-- exposes the current node for use with jstl -->
<body style="background-color:${pageProperties.bgcolor}" >]]></source>
                <p>
                    Save all files. We will find a new property called "Background Color" in our page properties dialog
                    box. Let us try it out and enter a HTML-color-code (lets say #aabbcc) and save. After reloading the
                    page, we will have a nice greyish-blue background.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <img src="../images/qs/04_magnolia_quickstartWebPageBackground.png" />
                </p>
                <p>
                    The
                    <code>cms:setNode</code>
                    tag is from our cms-taglib that we have made available at the start of our page template:
                </p>
                <source><![CDATA[<jsp:root version="2.0" ... xmlns:cms="cms-taglib">]]></source>
                <p>
                    <code>cms:setNode</code>
                    exposes the current page properties in order to access them using EL expressions. You can also use
                    the
                    <code>cms:out</code>
                    tag to directly print property values, if you don't need to nest them inside html attributes:
                    <source><![CDATA[<cms:out nodeDataName="bgcolor" />]]></source>.
                </p>
                <p>Congratulations! We have defined our first custom property for a page template.</p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
