<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Contribution</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Help Wanted!">
            <p>
                If you have some time on your hands and like what you see, why not participate and make Magnolia even
                better.
            </p>
            <p>
                There are many ways you can support us:
                <a href="word.html">spread the word</a>
                ,
                <a href="code.html">write code</a>
                or simply share time, knowledge or funds with us. We need you!
            </p>
            <subsection name="Answer questions on the mailing lists">
                <p>
                    Even if you just got started with Magnolia, you might know more than the guy asking a question. You
                    are very welcome to share your knowledge on our templaters mailing list.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Write documentation">
                <p>
                    If you like to write documentation and have some time on your hands, there are many issues that need
                    documenting. If you have learned something, write it down and share it. No need to get fancy with
                    graphics and stuff. A small how-to in plain text is a good start.
                </p>
                <p>
                    If you had to write documentation for your users, your IT department or your grandmom, why not share
                    it with the rest of the Magnolia community. They might have grandmoms, too.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Translate the Magnolia User Interface">
                <p>
                    Magnolia will come with an internationalization module. This allows Magnolia to have its user
                    interface in any language you like. Even if you do not have the ambitions to completely translate
                    Magnolia, you might have time to add a couple of translations or correct erraneous ones.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Report bugs">
                <p>
                    If you use Magnolia and find a bug, report it. Make sure its a bug (and not simply a configuration
                    issue), check the bug tracker if it has been reported before, and add it to the bug tracker if no
                    one else has done so.
                </p>
                <p>
                    If you don't know if something is a bug or a configuration problem, check the mailing list archives
                    for similar problems. If in doubt, post it on the list, and if the general agreement is that its a
                    bug, go add it to the bug tracker.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Of course you are also welcome to download the latest code from CVS and test it. Report bugs using
                    the bug tracker.
                </p>
                <p>See the feedback page for details on reporting bugs.</p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Other ideas? Let us know!</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Are you the creative type? Share your wicked ideas of promoting Magnolia with us!</p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>