<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Spread the word!</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Spread the word!">
            <p>
                If you like Magnolia, one way to help us is to promote us - spread the word about Magnolia. Here are a
                couple of ideas.
            </p>
            <subsection name="Report Magnolia sites and success stories">
                <p>
                    If you have built a website with Magnolia, let us know about it. We provide an easy to use web
                    interface to do so - simply fill out the blanks and we will add you to the growing list of
                    references.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Write about Magnolia">
                <p>
                    If you have the possibility to write an article about Magnolia, do so. Publish it on your blog, your
                    website or in a newspaper. Let us know about it, we might put a back link to it.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Talk about Magnolia">
                <p>
                    You are a conference speaker? Great! Talk about Magnolia - even if you only mention it, you will
                    help Magnolia to gain more popularity. Of course, you are also welcome to speak about Magnolia on
                    the Radio or the TV evening news. If all else fails, talk to your dog. It is unlikely to
                    significantly promote Magnolia, but maybe it helps your dog.
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Link to Magnolia">
                <p>
                    You have created a website with Magnolia or simply like what we do? Link to us! You can download the
                    "Made with Magnolia" logo or simply put a link on your web page. Of course we are also happy if you
                    let us know about your Magnolia site, so that we can link to you.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
