<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Introduction</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="1. Introduction">
            <p>
                <strong>
                    The following examples assume that you have Magnolia installed and up and running inside tomcat,
                    which is currently our default distribution. If you use a different J2EE server, adjust your
                    thinking accordingly. For installation, follow the release notes available with the distribution of
                    Magnolia.
                </strong>
            </p>
            <p>
                Magnolia per default has installed two applications: authoring and public. The applications are
                basically identical, but can run on different instances or even different servers. It makes sense to
                start building templates inside the authoring application folder, so that you can try out your
                templates. Once your templates work as desired, you will have to copy these to the public application
                folder to see their output in the published website as well.
            </p>
            <p>
                Inside of the webapps folder of tomcat, you will find the magnolia application
                (INSTALLDIR/magnolia/author/webapps/magnolia),
            </p>
            <p>The folder contents are more or less as follows:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>WEB-INF/</li>
                <li>admindocroot/</li>
                <li>admintemplates/</li>
                <li>cache/</li>
                <li>docroot/</li>
                <li>logs/</li>
                <li>repository/</li>
                <li>templates/</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                For the course of this tutorial, all we really need to know is: templates go to
                INSTALLDIR/magnolia/author/webapps/magnolia/templates.
            </p>
            <p>
                admindocroot and admintemplates contain files relevant for Magnolia administration, cache will contain a
                cache of our website. The docroot folder can be used to put files there that we would like to access via
                standard web mechanisms (e.g. static links). The repository will contain all content, as well as users,
                roles and custom configuration, including the information which templates are available. The templates
                directory contains the JSP templates that define the look (and functionality) of our website.
            </p>
            <p>
                Templates exist on two levels - we create templates for pages, and we create templates for paragraphs.
                The page template will commonly contain things like the html head, css includes, Javascript and
                navigation.
            </p>
            <p>
                Paragraph templates will be used to define the look (and functionality) of paragraphs. Examples might be
                an image paragraph, a text with heading and subtitle or a form designer to collect all those valuable
                tidbits your marketing department has been demanding for the last twenty-three earlymorning strategy
                meetings.
            </p>
            <p>
                One way to determine what goes where is that all the things that we only need once per page or have a
                fixed place on the page (e.g. a logo) could be part of the page template, and all the bits that we might
                move around on the page or that occur multiple times (e.g. text blocks or images), will probably end up
                as some kind of paragraph.
            </p>
            <p>
                From a different perspective, one can think of a paragraph definition as a mapping between the view and
                the model. The view is defined through a JSP template (or a servlet), and the model is defined through a
                dialog definition. More about that later.
            </p>
            <p>We will first look at page templates, then at paragraph templates.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>