<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Magnolia User List</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Magnolia User List">
            <p>
                If you want to develop web-sites with Magnolia, feel free to subscribe to the Magnolia user mailing
                list. (simply send an empty email). You can cancel at any time
            </p>
            <p>
                to subscribe send a mail to:
                <a href="mailto:user-list-subscribe@magnolia.info">user-list-subscribe@magnolia.info</a>
            <br />
                    to post send mails to:
                <a href="mailto:user-list@magnolia.info">user-list@magnolia.info</a>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        We only accept plain text email on this list. If you are a windows user, by default that
                        requirement will not be met. Please read
                        <a href="http://expita.com/nomime.html" target="_blank">
                            "Configuring Mail Clients to Send Plain ASCII Text"
                        </a>
                        to understand what is wrong with non-ASCII mail and what you can do about it. Even if that is
                        the only thing you get out of visiting magnolia.info, it will be worth it.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Please be sure to check the
                        <a target="_blank" href="http://webmail.magnolia.info/Lists/user-list/List.html">archive</a>
                        first. Your mail might not get answered if it has been answered before.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Trim your replies. That means do not simply hit "Reply" and start typing. Remove anything that
                        is not directly relevant to your reply before you start typing. We all have the previous mail in
                        our inbox, there is no need to have the whole thread copied into each reply.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Be concise - provide as much detail as necessary and as little as possible to state your case.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        If you want to get the most out of the mailing list, take the time to read
                        <a target="_blank" href="http://www.catb.org/%7Eesr/faqs/smart-questions.html">
                            asking smart questions
                        </a>
                        , a great article by Eric S. Raymond. Its the best article on the web about asking questions on
                        mailing lists bar none.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Keep in mind that all information and answers are provided by volunteers. Commercial support
                        packages are available through partners of the Magnolia partner network.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            <br />
                You can unsubscribe at any time by sending an empty email to
                <a href="mailto:user-list-off@magnolia.info">user-list-off@magnolia.info</a>
            <br />
                To switch to the DIGEST mode, send an empty email to
                <a href="mailto:user-list-digest@magnolia.info">user-list-digest@magnolia.info</a>
            <br />
                To switch to the INDEX mode, send an empty email to
                <a href="mailto:user-list-index@magnolia.info">user-list-index@magnolia.info</a>
            <br />
                For any administrative enquieries, please use
                <a href="mailto:user-list-request@magnolia.info">user-list-request@magnolia.info</a>
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>